Preliminary Inventory to the Frederick Nossal papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Frederick Nossal papers
1944-1979
80010
Nossal, Frederick, 1927-
68 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 2 scrapbooks (29.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Drafts of writings, dispatches, clippings, serial issues, other printed matter, photographs, and slides, relating to political and other conditions in China, the Vietnamese War, political conditions elsewhere in Asia, and activities of the World Bank.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
International Bank for Reconstruction and Development.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975.; Asia.; Asia--Politics and government.; China.; China--Description and travel.; China--Politics and government--1949-1976.; Journalists.
Biography
Canadian journalist; Far East correspondent, 1959-1971, stationed in Peking, 1959-1960; information officer, World Bank, 1971-1979.
Container List
- Serial issues and other printed matter on China (Box 1)
- Serial issues and other printed matter on China (Box 2)
- Cables to the Toronto Telegram by Nossal, Sept. 1967-June 1968
- Cables to the Toronto Telegram from Vietnam by Nossal, Jan.-May 1968
- Cables to the Toronto Telegram by Nossal, Apr.-June 1968 (Box 3)
- Syndicated articles by Nossal, 1969
- Toronto Telegram articles by Nossal, 1971
- Typescript of special articles by Nossal, 1968 (Box 4)
- Typescript of articles by Nossal, 1968
- Cables to the Toronto Telegram by Nossal, Sept. 1967-Jan. 1968
- Toronto Telegram articles by Nossal
- Page proofs of China: The Great Unknown (Box 5)
- Printed matter and miscellany
- Articles by Nossal on Macao and Malaysia (Box 6)
- Toronto Telegram articles by Nossal, 1968
- Toronto Telegram articles by Nossal, 1969-1970
- Articles by Nossal on Hong Kong, Macao and Vietnam (Box 7)
- Synopsis of projected book by Nossal
- Articles by Nossal ready for typing for book
- Ideas for book
- Current material for book
- Articles by Nossal on Laos (Box 72)
- Articles by Nossal on India and Japan (Box 13)
- Typescript articles by Nossal (Box 8)
- Typescript articles by Nossal for book
- Articles from Peking by Nossal
- Articles by Nossal on population and Mao
- Plan for book by Nossal, Strangers in Asia
- Articles by Nossal, mainly on Vietnam
- Articles by Nossal on world philosophy and Vietnam (Box 9)
- Articles by Nossal on Laos
- Articles by Nossal on Asia, China and exodus from China
- Articles by Nossal
- Articles by Nossal on Vietnam (Box 72)
- Rough drafts of articles by Nossal, 1968 (Box 10)
- Printed matter, mainly on China
- Book reviews by Nossal, 1960-1967 (Box 11)
- Articles by Nossal on communism, politics, trade and the atomic bomb in China
- Photographs of Vietnam
- Miscellaneous printed matter
- Hiroshima - printed matter
- Articles by Nossal for the Melbourne Herald
- Articles by Nossal on a Far East diary, Asia and Burma (Box 12)
- Articles by Nossal on exodus from China
- Reviews of and articles from Nossal's book Dateline Peking
- Correspondence with Macdonald and Co. (Publisher) (Box 13)
- Dateline Peking articles by Nossal
- Articles by Nossal on China
- Articles by Nossal on Hong Kong
- Articles by Nossal on Sino-Soviet rift (Box 14)
- Articles by Nossal on poverty
- Articles by Nossal on Laos
- Correspondence on China
- Articles by Nossal on China
- Serial issues, pamphlets and other printed matter, mainly on China (Box 15)
- Miscellaneous issues of the Toronto Globe and Mail (Box 16)
- Miscellaneous issues of the Totonto Globe and Mail and other periodicals (Box 17)
- Serial issues and other printed matter on Asia (Box 18)
- U.S. Navy in Vietnam - issuances by the U.S. Navy
- Correspondence on lectures in Canada, 1962-1967
- Serial issues and other printed matter (Box 19)
- Issues of the Sun Junior (Sydney), 1944-1946
- Early published articles by Nossal
- Trip to India, 1967
- Vietnam Subject File (Box 20)
  - Vietnam political, 1971
  - Vietnam pacification
  - Vietnam history
  - South Vietnam war, 1971
  - Vietnam economy
  - After the war
  - Atrocities
  - Ceasefire
  - Coalition
  - Dien Bien Phu
  - Dissent
  - Escalation
  - International Control Commission
  - Nguyen Van Thieu (Box 21)
  - Peace talks, 1971
  - Personalities
  - Ralliers
  - Troops
  - Vietnamization
  - Withdrawal
  - South Vietnam-Canada relations
  - South Vietnam-U.S. relations
  - North Vietnam war, 1971 (Box 22)
  - North Vietnam bombings
  - National Liberation Front
  - North Vietnam personalities
  - North Vietnam-China relations
  - North Vietnam-Russia relations
  - North Vietnam-U.S. relations
  - South Vietnam war, 1970
  - South Vietnam war, 1969
  - Vietnam political, 1970
  - Peace talks, 1970
  - North Vietnam, 1970
- China Subject File (Box 23)
  - China, 1970-1971
  - Sino-Soviet clash, 1970
  - Sino-Soviet rift, 1970
  - China history
  - China-Albania relations
  - China-Britain relations, 1971
  - China-Canada relations, 1970-1971
  - China-Hong Kong relations
  - China-Japan relations
  - China-Russia relations (Box 24)
  - Indochina war
  - China-U.N. relations, 1970-1971
  - China-U.S. relations
  - Armed forces (Box 25)
  - Canton Fair
  - China defenses
  - Detainees
  - Economy
  - Education
  - China's enemies
  - Foreign relations, 1971
  - General
  - Leaders
  - Military dictatorship
  - National Day (Box 26)
  - Negroes
  - Nuclear
  - Overseas Chinese
  - Party congress
  - Personalities
  - Political
  - Population
  - Revolutionary councils
  - China space
  - Trade
  - China's youth
  - 9th party congress, 1969
  - China-Britain relations, 1967-1969 (Box 27)
  - China political, 1967-1969
  - Sino-Soviet stories
  - India trip (Box 28)
  - Sino-Soviet clash, 1969
- General Subject File
  - Ho Chi Minh
  - Lin Piao
  - Chou En-lai
  - Disarmament
  - Famine
  - Giap (Vo Nguyen)
  - Aid
  - Liu Shao-chi (Box 29)
  - Mao Tse-tung
  - Marcos (Ferdinand)
  - Mekong development
  - NATO
  - Neutralism
  - Nixon (Richard M.)
  - Nuclear treaties
  - Population
  - Personalities
  - Sako (Eisatu) (Box 30)
  - SEATO
  - Serve the people
  - Souvanna Phouma
  - Soviet congress
  - Suharto
  - Tourism
  - Tengku Abdul Rahman
  - Trudeau (Pierre)
  - UNCTAD
  - Pamphlets and articles
  - Cultural Revolution (Box 31)
  - Foreign relations of China, 1967-1970
  - Cambodia, May 1, 1970
  - Vietnam political (Box 32)
  - Tet 1968
  - Thieu (Nguyen Van), 1968
  - South Vietnam war, 1969 (Box 33)
  - South Vietnam elections, 1968
  - North Vietnam (Box 34)
  - Saigon, 1968
- Published articles by Nossal, 1960-1979 (Box 35)
- Press cards and notebooks
- Printed copies in English, French, Spanish and Japanese of Nossal's book Dateline - Peking (1962) (Box 36)
- Editorials by Nossal for the United Church, Toronto, 1973-1976 (Box 37)
- Memoranda on China by Nossal for the World Bank, 1972-1973
- Published articles by Nossal, 1948-1959
- Articles by Nossal for possible talks (Box 38)
- Printed matter on Bangladesh
- Miscellany
- Material from Peking
- References and terms with the Toronto Telegram, 1967
- Photographs of Canadian aid to Vietnam
- Published articles
- Typescript articles by Nossal, 1968 (Box 39)
- Business letters, 1972-1975
- Notes and notebooks on Vietnam
- Newspaper issues (Box 40)
- Articles by Nossal for the South China Morning Post
- Slides of Hong Kong (Box 41)
- Slides of demonstrations in China
- Miscellaneous slides and photographs
- Slides and photographs of Hong Kong, India and Luang Probang, 1959-1962 (Box 42)
- Miscellaneous negatives
- Slides taken on World Bank missions, 1971-1979 (Box 43)
- Negatives of China
- Slides (Box 44)
- Negatives of China
- Slides of China, 1959-1960 (Box 45)
- Articles by Nossal for the World Bank
- Pamphlets, serial issues and other printed matter on Asia (Box 46)
- Pamphlets, serial issues and other printed matter on Asia (Box 47)
- Miscellany relating to the World Bank
- Clippings on Vietnam, 1964-1967 (Box 48)
- Toronto Globe and Mail Focus articles by Nossal, 1965-1967
- Toronto Globe and Mail Focus articles by Nossal, and others, 1960-1964
- Clippings on Southeast Asia, 1964-1967
- Algiers - photographs (Box 49)
- India - photographs
- Malaya - photographs
- Laos - photographs
- Japan - photographs
- Macao - photographs
- World Bank material on China
- World Bank - clippings
- Published articles by Nossal for the World Bank
- Hong Kong - photographs (Box 50)
- Vietnam, 1969 - photographs
- Vietnam, 1967-1971 - photographs for the Toronto Telegram
- China - photographs (Box 51)
- Vietnam, 1968 - photographs
- General - photographs
- Pamphlets, serial issues and other printed matter on Asia (Box 52)
- Clippings on China, communism, the U.N., India, Pakistan and Kashmir, 1964-1967
- Business cards of acquaintances (Box 53)
- Miscellaneous printed matter
- Maps, 1959-1971 (Box 54)
- Serial issues
- New job, 1971 - resume and correspondence (Box 55)
- Dragon Lodge, Hong Kong - financial records
- Letters
- Articles by Nossal for the Australian Financial Review
- Financial records
- Articles by Nossal for the Far Eastern Economic Review and related correspondence, 1960-1970
- Correspondence with editors
- Business cards of acquaintances (Box 56)
- Miscellaneous serial issues and clippings
- Cables to the Toronto Telegram, 1968
- Trip to Japan, 1969 (Box 57)
- Eye on China articles, 1967-1969
- Miscellaneous issues of the Toronto Telegram and other newspapers
- Articles by Nossal for the Toronto Telegram, 1968 (Box 58)
- Clippings and miscellaneous serial issues
- Articles by Nossal for the World Bank, 1971-1979
- World Bank memoranda
- Cables to the Toronto Telegram, Oct.-Dec. 1970 (Box 59)
- Published articles by Nossal in the Toronto Telegram, 1968-1969
- Cables to the Toronto Telegram, Sept.-Nov. 1968
- Rough drafts of articles by Nossal, 1968
- Syndicated articles by Nossal, 1969
- Typescript articles by Nossal for the Toronto Telegram, Nov. 1968-Feb. 1969 (Box 60)
- Typescripts and cables of articles by Nossal for the Toronto Telegram, sent from Hong Kong, June 1970
- Writings by Nossal for CFTO-TV, Toronto
- Typescript articles by Nossal for the Toronto Telegram, Aug.-Oct. 1969 (Box 61)
- Rough drafts of articles by Nossal for the Toronto Telegram, Aug.-Nov. 1969
- Typescripts and cables of articles by Nossal for the Toronto Telegram, Aug.-Oct. 1969
- Rough drafts of articles by Nossal for the Toronto Telegram, Jan.-July 1969
- Typescripts of articles by Nossal for the Toronto Telegram, Jan.-June 1969
- Typescripts and cables of articles by Nossal for the Toronto Telegram, Sept. 1970
- Cables to the Toronto Telegram, May 12-Aug. 5, 1969
- Miscellany
- Financial records
- Typescripts and cables of articles by Nossal to the Toronto Telegram, Jan.-Mar. 1970
- Typescripts and cables of articles by Nossal for the Toronto Telegram (Box 62)
- Advisory cables to Nossal from the Toronto Telegram, 1970
- Cables to the Toronto Telegram, Jan.-Feb. 1971
- Articles by Nossal on Asia
- Toronto Globe and Mail announcements (Box 63)
- Business correspondence with the Toronto Telegram, 1967-1969
- Published talks by others
- Early articles by Nossal (Box 64)
- Articles by Nossal on the tour of the British royal family, 1958
- Articles by Nossal for the Toronto Globe and Mail
- Typescript articles by Nossal, 1962-1966
- World Bank papers (Box 65)
- New job, 1971 - applications and letters
- Insurance records
- Move from Hong Kong, 1971 - financial records and correspondence
- Business letters, 1970-1971 (Box 66)
- Toronto Telegram - financial records and correspondence
- Toronto Telegram - correspondence (Box 67)
- China-U.N. relations, 1962-1969
- Clippings of Nossal's articles on China from the Toronto Globe and Mail, 1959-1960 (Box 68)
- Clippings of Nossal's articles on China from the Toronto Telegram, 1967-1971
- Clippings of Nossal's articles on the Vietnam Tet offensive from the Toronto Telegram, 1968 (Box 69)
- Clippings of Nossal's articles on Vietnam from the Toronto Telegram, 1967-1971
- Clippings of Nossal's articles on Asia from the Toronto Telegram, 1967-1971
- Clippings of Nossal's articles from the South China Morning Post (Hong Kong) and other newspapers, 1959-1971 (Volume 70)
- Clippings of Nossal's articles from the Toronto Telegram, 1967-1971 (Volume 71)